

# Cihad Cengiz Full Stack Developer

+90 544 673-7603

cihadcengiz.com

Istanbul, Turkey

#### SUMMARY

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 3 years of related experience.

#### EXPERIENCE

 Full Stack Developer
 02/2022 - 05/2022

Extramus.eu

- Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans.
- · Worked with back-end developers to design APIs.
- Used PHP Laravel, Sequelize and MongoDB to develop and manage databases.
- Developed clear specifications for project plans using customer requirements.
- · Mentored junior members and delivered training to boost team skills set.

**Web Developer Intern** 01/2019 - 06/2019

E2 Design

- · Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Developed functional databases, applications and servers to support websites on back-end.
- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5 and CSS3.
- Troubleshot and debugged code ensuring compatibility with devices, browsers and operating systems.
- Wrote custom HTML and JavaScript for existing websites.
- Used content creation tools and digital media to design web sites.

#### EDUCATION

Management Information Systems Anadolu University - Bachelor's Degree	2024
Computer Programming Eskisehir Technical University - Associate of Applied Science	2021
Information Technology and Computer Science Vilnius University - Bachelor's Degree	2020
Computer Programming Istanbul Aydin University - Associate of Applied Science	2020

## CERTIFICATES

Traditional Entrepreneurship Training - KOSGEB	04/2021 - Present
Python for Machine Learning - ESTU Data Sciences	04/2021 - Present
Python Core - SoloLearn	02/2021 - Present
Why R? Turkey 2021 – Why R? Foundation	02/2021 - Present
React-Redux - SoloLearn	01/2021 - Present
Javascript - SoloLearn	01/2021 - Present
CSS - SoloLearn	03/2020 - Present
HTML - SoloLearn	03/2020 - Present
Java - SoloLearn	02/2020 - Present
C++ - SoloLearn	01/2020 - Present

## SKILLS

Javascript	Advanced	Python	Intermediate
React.js	Advanced	C++	Intermediate
Node.js	Advanced	C#	Intermediate
Express.js	Advanced	С	Intermediate
MongoDB	Beginner	Redux	Intermediate
PostgreSQL	Intermediate	Docker	Beginner
SQL	Intermediate	Bootstrap	Intermediate
SequelizeORM	Advanced		

## LANGUAGES

Turkish	Native	German	Basic
English	Fluent		